

Full Stack Developer with ~4 years of experience in analysis, design, and development of various applications at different stages of the software development life cycle. Demonstrated success with problem-solving abilities and have a high desire to learn new skills.

Howrah • West Bengal • India

(+91) 89813 80649

M dsaikat378@gmail.com

in /iamsaikat

(7) /deysaikat04

SKILLS

JavaScript	TypeScript	Python	jQuery	ReactJS	Redux
Redux Toolkit	React Query	NodeJS	ExpressJS	NestJS	MySQL
PostgreSQL	MongoDB	Prisma	Firebase	GCP	Azure
Jest	GIT	Web securities	HTML	CSS	SASS
Tailwind CSS	Material UI				

EXPERIENCES

PropertyLoop — London, United Kingdom

Development Team Lead (Remote)

JUL 2022 – PRESENT

- Responsible for strategizing plans to achieve team goals promptly within the stipulated time frame
- Developed a robust Role Based Access Control system for all organizational products, boosting security and user accessibility
- Implemented code review and optimization practices resulting in a 20% reduction in overall lines of code which led to improved system performance and a 30% reduction in bug reports
- Taking part in design discussions and providing suggestions that satisfy business requirements and parallelly improve user engagement by up to 10%
- Actively contributed to requirement refinements, resulting in a 20% reduction in project rework and a 10% improvement in overall project efficiency
- Enabling team members in feature development by ensuring smoother workflow, schedule, and appropriate delegation of work

Full Stack Developer (Remote)

JAN 2022 – JUL 2022

- Leveraged third-party integrations to analyze user behavior and identify common drop-off points, driving a remarkable 50% improvement in customer retention
- Implemented Single Sign-On (SSO) to simplify the sign-up process, resulting in a 10% increase in user registration
- Suggested UI/UX modifications to business that helped in user efficiency
- Developed scalable and efficient RESTful APIs for the backend, ensuring optimal performance and seamless integration
- Integrated scalable Azure HTTP trigger functions leading to a 10% increase in property advertisements or marketing reach

Saikat Dey 1

Infosys — Bhubaneswar, India

Systems Engineer (Remote)

MAR 2021 - JAN 2022

- Developed and delivered a complete module of a fintech product, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement
- Increased user efficiency by automating workflows, resulting in a significant amount of reduction in task completion time
- Added unit tests that improved test coverage from 65% to 95%, leading to a 75% decrease in critical bugs and a 20% increase in overall code quality
- Enforced best practices within the team for better development experience

AUG 2020 - MAR 2021

- Developed features that helped users to move from MS Excel to a web application which in turn, improved user efficiency
- Worked on query optimization that significantly improved API response time
- Improved unit test coverage from 70% to 90%

Infosys — Mysore, India

Systems Engineer Trainee

JAN 2020 - AUG 2020

- Developed an eCommerce application with RESTful web services using MERN stack
- Added unit test cases for both frontend and backend

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Promoted to Team Lead at PropertyLoop within six months of joining, in recognition of outstanding performance and leadership abilities
- Received a commendation from onsite clients at Infosys for successfully developing and delivering a highly anticipated application from scratch, incorporating my innovative suggestions
- Achieved an impressive score of around 84% and secured the prestigious HPF tag in Infosys Training

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology — Computer Science and Engineering

AUG 2016 - JUL 2019

Achieved Bachelor's degree from Heritage Institute of Technology with 8.03 DGPA

Saikat Dey 2